Preliminary Guide to the John C. Lilly papers M0786
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John C. Lilly papers
1933-2012
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Lilly, John Cunningham
M0786
242 Linear Feet
154 box(es) (processed portion only)
The John C. Lilly papers contain a variety of material relating over fifty years of his research in marine biology, neuroscience, and related fields.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy. Selected audiovisual media have been reformatted.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1996-2015. Accessions 1996-033, 2004-056, 2012-052, 2014-009, and 2015-096.
Biographical / Historical
John Cunningham Lilly (1915-2001) was a physiologist, biologist, and medical doctor known for his work with dolphins and interspecies communication, as well as research on the brain and consciousness which resulted in his invention of the isolation tank.
Lilly was born the son of a banker in St. Paul, Minnesota. He attended the California Institute of Technology, graduating in 1938 with Physics and Biology degrees. He then attended medical school at Dartmouth and the University of Pennsylvania. During World War II, he conducted experiments on the physiological effect of high altitudes, which began his investigation into brain function. After the war he trained as a psychoanalyst and conducted brain research for the National Institutes of Health, including the development of techniques for electrical stimulation of the brain. In 1954 he devised a sensory deprivation tank, and later began self-administering LSD and other drugs in the solitude of the tank. Lilly’s counterculture ideas and lifestyle made him contemporaries with such figures as Timothy Leary, Ram Dass, and Werner Erhard (all frequent guests at Lilly’s home), but it also invited skepticism from more conservative scientists.
His tank experiments led to an interest in aquatic life, especially cetaceans, and in 1959 he established the Communication Research Institute in Miami and the Virgin Islands to study the vocalizations of bottle-nosed dolphins. Further research into dolphin communication was conducted at the JANUS (Joint Analog Numerical Understanding System) Project in San Francisco, using computers to interpret dolphin speech. Lilly created the non-profit Human Dolphin Foundation in Malibu, California in 1976. He is the author of 19 books, including Man and Dolphin, The Center of the Cyclone, and an autobiography The Scientist, as well as hundreds of papers. Lilly retired to Maui in 1992 and died of heart failure at the age of 86. The John C. Lilly Research Institute continues his research.
Preserved media
Audio has been digitally captured from reels in Box 79, 82, 99, 105, 106, 108 and 120. Videocassettes in Box 144 have also been transferred.
Separated Materials
For computer media, see MSS MEDIA 0026 [3 disks].
Scope and Contents
The collection contains manuscripts, scientific articles and papers, notes, correspondence, recordings and logs of dolphin experiments, and audiovisual media relating to Lilly's various research interests, including dolphins, sensory deprivation, psychoactive drugs, neuroscience and electrical stimulation of the brain, human-animal relations, computers, and other subjects.
Animal communication; Animal intelligence; Physicians -- History.; Dolphins -- Behavior.; Hallucinogenic drugs.; LSD (Drug); Lilly, John Cunningham; Lilly, John Cunningham
- Series 1. Correspondence and files [A-Z]
  - Altes, R.A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Physiological Society (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ANIMA (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Animal Protection Institute USA (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Animal Welfare Institute (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Cetacean Society (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Atkinson, Dinni (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Apple Computers (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Janus Symbol Artwork (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Australia, Whaling (Sir Sydney Frost) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Authors League (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - A Correspondence A (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Batteau, Dwight (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - B Correspondence B (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Richard Bach (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Baker, Byrd (Mendocino Whale War) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bantam Books (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bendix, Michael (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - AMASA & Barbara Bishop 81-82 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Benson, Paul (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - Blue Water Wetsuits (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Boats (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bonny, Helen L. Dr. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Michael J. Bowers (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brandy Brandis (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brazier, Dr. M.A. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Brenner, Malcolm (Box 55, Folder 15)
  - Brenner, Malcolm, Some Observations on Aspects of Interspecies Communications between Man and Bottlenosed Dolphins, typescript, 1970-1971 (Box 55, Folder 16)
  - Bridges, Jeff & Susan (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brochures (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brockman, John (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brown, Robin (Lure of the Dolphins) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Spencer Brown (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Buhr, Bob (Box 55, Folder 17)
  - Bud Bottoms (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bullock, Theodore (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Bullock, Theodore (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Bullock, Theodore (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - C Correspondence C (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - California Pacific Adventures (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Campbell, Douglas A. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cannon Island (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cetacean Relations (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Centre for Ocean Studies (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Chimp Communication, Duane Rumbaugh (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Chimp Communication, Roger Fouts (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Barbara Clarke Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Cetacea Information (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Computer Games/Dolphins Contacts etc. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Conger, Steven (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cohen, Sidney (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Connecticut Cetacean Society (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Coury, Fred (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - C Correspondence C (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cetus Article (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Pete Cornell (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Cousteau Society (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Christian Science Monitor (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Cybernetics (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dana Point Harbor (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Dawn of Atlas - Research Company, Marine Mammal vertebrae (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Defenders of Wildlife (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - de la Flor, Francesca (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Demetrios, Michael B. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - di Suvero, Victor (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - di Suvero, Victor (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - di Suvero, Victor (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Diercks, K.J. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Horace Dobbs (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - D Correspondence D (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Digital Voice (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Diving Information (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Decus Membership (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Dolger, Jonathan (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Dolphin Research Center (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Downing, Joseph, M.D. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Wade Doak (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dolphin Action and Protection Group, Cape Town, South Africa (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dolphin Embassy (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Dolphin Brains - Peter Morgane (Box 4, Folders 4-5)
  - Dolphin Release 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Articles (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Wholistic Health (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - E Correspondence E (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Institute of Echotechnics (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Ed Ellsworth (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Endangered Species Production (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Environmental Defense Fund (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Erhard, Werner (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Erickson Educational Foundation (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - CRI - Erickson Project (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Essentia (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Evans, Bill 1983 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Evans, William (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Evans, William (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - The Explorers Club (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Extinction of Species (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - F Correspondence F (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Film Proposals (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Feynman, Richard (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Florida Property (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Pieter Folkens (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Fortom-Gouin, Jean Paul (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Friends of Cetacean List (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Friends of the Earth (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Fundraising & Fundraisers (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - The Hunt Foundation (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - The Macarthur Foundation (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - G Correspondence G (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Gazebo (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - General Whale (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Amit Goswami, University of Oregon (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Roedy Green (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Greenpeace Foundation (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Stan and Christina Grof, Spiritual Emergency Network (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - H correspondence (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Haida Killer Whale (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hawaii - Sheraton (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hawaii - School (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Tom Wilkes Hawaii Project (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Herbert, Frank (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Lou Herman (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Holt, Sidney (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Holt, Sidney (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Albert Hoffman (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Houston Tank Center (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - The Hunt Foundation (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - E.F. Hutton Stockbrokers (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Hubbs - Sea World Research Institute (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Huxley, Laura (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Kona (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Human/Dolphin Malibu Office Procedures (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - For Toni/HDF Malibu (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - HDF - Germany (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Inquiry into Whales & Whaling (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Institute for Delphinid Research (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Institute for Ethnographic Studies (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Institute for Environmental Studies (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - International Fund for Animal Welfare (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Invitation to Brunch, Jan. 4, 1981 / Christmas Letter, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - I Correspondence I (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Dolphin Release - 1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - IWC Whales Alive (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - IWC July 18-23 Brighton (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - International Whaling Commission 1983 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Island Foundation 81-82 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Interspecies Communication (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Interspecies Communication (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - J Correspondence J (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Jean, Paule (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Francis Jeffrey (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Jojoba Project (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Hardy Jones (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Journal of Mind and Behavior, Ray Russ (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - K Correspondence K (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Kellerman (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Kert, John (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Jean Knights (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Knights, Jean (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Knights, Jean (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Ketamine, CNS and (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - National Science Foundation 1980 Proposal (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - NSF Proposals - Copies (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Human Dolphin Proposal 4/1/80 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Final Proposal as Submitted to National Science Foundation 5/80 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Le Furgy, William (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Le Furgy, William, April 12, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Levine, Joseph (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Lightforce Spirulina Company (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The Living Music Foundation (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - LSD into the 80's Unity Press (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - LSD (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Llewellyn Publications (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Laguna Soap Company (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lilly
    - Medicare: JCL (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - J.C. Lilly Donations to HDF (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Writings for a New Book J.C.L. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - John C. Lilly Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Lilly, Cynthia (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - John C. Lilly - request for information under Freedom of Information Act (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Marine Action Centre (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Society of Marine Mammalogists (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Marine Mammal Society (Proposed) (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Maui Whale Research Institute (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Maturana, Humberto (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Megaw, W.J. (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Dan Melnick (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Ernst L. Moerk, Ph.D., Cal State Dept. of Psychology (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - College Mailing List (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Victoria Kingston Mudd (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Estelle Myers Project Interlock (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - M Correspondence M (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Joan McKenna (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Mariko Omura - Maxy - Japan (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Macintosh (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Marine Mammal Commission (Box 9, Folders 30-31)
  - Marine Mammals Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Merrell-Wolfe, Franklin (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Marine Life Correspondence Re Dolphins "Joe" and "Rosalie" (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Marine World
    - Marine World Reports by HDF Staff (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Marine World/Africa USA (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Marine World Mishigas (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Marine World Workshop (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Tom Fitz Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Marine World Executive Committee (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Redwood City Expenses (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - OZMA Productions (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Visual Discrimination (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Marine World Miscellaneous HDF (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Marine World Reorganization HDF/MW, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Marine World Organizational Structure Governing HDF October 1983 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Roberta Quist (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Work Scholars (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Marine World Janus 3 Reports (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Mote Marine Lab (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Natural Organics (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - National Marine Fisheries Service (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - New Alchemists (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - New Frontiers Institute (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - New York Academy of Sciences (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Norris, Kenneth S. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - North-South Foundation (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - N Correspondence N (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Nova 1983 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Rick Trout Ocean Reef Club - Florida (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Ocean Contact (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Oceanic Society (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Oregonians Co-operating to Protect Whales & Dolphins (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Overland, Mark (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Oceans - Magazines (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Oceans - Letters, etc. (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - O Correspondence O (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Patrick Walsh Press (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Price, Richard and Chris (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Prince, Renee (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - R correspondence (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Robson, Frank (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Sanders, Molly (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Sugarman, Peter (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - Tart, Charles (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - Tyler, Martha (Box 57, Folder 23)
  - Schaeffer, Lance (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Silverman, Julian (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Soidla, T.R. (Leningrad University) (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Stanback, Brad (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - Stewart, John II (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - Tanner, Georgia (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Tors, Ivan (Box 57, Folder 20)
  - Torkelson, David (Box 57, Folder 21)
  - Truby, H. M. (Box 57, Folder 22)
  - Vanzant, Tom (Box 57, Folder 24)
  - Vassar, David (Box 57, Folder 25)
  - Verschur, Gerrit (Box 57, Folder 26)
  - Varela, Francisco J. (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Varela, Francisco J. (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Varela, Francisco J. (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Varela, Francisco J. (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Wacker, Charles (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Wagner, Byron (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Weilgart, John (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Winter, Paul (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Wood, F.G. (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Worden, Fred (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - WXYZ correspondence (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 58, Folder 13)
- Series 2. Human/Dolphin Foundation (etc.), circa 1977-1985
  Scope and Contents
  Contains material about administration, funding, grants, and Board.
  - 2.1 National Science Foundation
    - NSF Correspondence 1977-78 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - NSF Proposal 1979 semi-final version (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - NSF Proposal 1979 Diagrams and Original (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - NSF Proposal 1979 Working papers (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - H/D FDN Proposal to NSF 1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - NSF Proposal 1979 Basic (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - NSF - Originals (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - NSF - Miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - NSF Proposal - July, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 2.4 Redwood City
    - Redwood City meetings (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Redwood City personal correspondence (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Redwood City organizational (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Redwood City Publicity Reports (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Redwood City Mail (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - 2.2 National Institute of Health
    - National Institute of Health (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - NIH - Draft (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - NIH - Background (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - NIH - Originals (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - NIH Addendum: Corrections & Additions to Proposal (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - NIH - Grant Application (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 2.3 JANUS
    - Janus Movie (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Janus - Esperanto (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Janus Myth (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Project Janus Library (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Janus Budget (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Janus Speech Synthesizers (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Newsletter Art & Cutouts (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Purchases 1984 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Taras Kiceniuk, Jr. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting September 27, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Dolphin-Human Housing (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Paid Bills - Pink Slips 1985 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Interviews by Toni (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Bank of America Car Loan, Dolfin (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Employment Applications (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Finances (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - American Express (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Media Proposals (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Revcon Bank of America Loan (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Proposal to DEC and others for equipment 1984 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - J David Contributors 1983 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - AL/JCL Medical - 1982 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - HDF Expenses/Funding (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Board Meeting July 8, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Bank of America Rec Ven 83 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Board Meeting August 29, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Careyes - Legal (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Board Meeting August 28, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Board Meeting June 1982 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Board Meeting Sept 12 1983 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Board Meeting Sept 12 1983 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Marine World (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Ruff Willie (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Board Meeting Dec 13, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - IRS: Letter of Tax Exempt Status & Other Communication (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Board Meeting August 23, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Transcript of 1/28/81 meeting of Trustees and Fundraiser, Bob Macgill (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Workshop Transcript (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Oasis Center (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Sea Window (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - American National Telcom (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Board Meeting March 7, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Proposals (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Island Foundation Proposal (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Grant Information (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - HDF Proposal July 27, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Proposals H/DF Peter Sugarman (Battelle Foundation) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Index (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - General (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Education (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Marineland Trips (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Literature (Box 15, Folders 8-9)
  - Vehicles & Gear (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Facilities, Janus, Mobile Lab, and Oceanarium (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Mobile Lab (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Trucks & Vans (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Release Forms (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Careyes (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Cannon Island (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Diving Gear (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Expenses (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Analogue Janus (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Audio/Video (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - B&K Instruments (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Computer Accessories (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - DEC - (Bills/Invoices/etc) (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - DEC - Maintenance (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - HDF Appeal Letters, JCL Annual Report Members & Friends (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - DEC - RT-11 V3B (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Support H/DF (Peter Sugarman) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Zodiac (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Hydrophones (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Abstract of Scientific Research Proposal (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Texas Instruments (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Tektronix (Oscilloscope) (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Spectral Dynamics (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Rack Mounting (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Pulse Transformers (Pico Electronics) (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - MDB Line Printer (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Lab Books (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Maintenance (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Hewlett Packard (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Heathkits (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Floppy Disks (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Telephone Conversations (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - National Marine Fisheries Service, Application for Permit - Dolphins (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous + Cassette (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Program for Research in the H/D F Jan 77 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - H/D Permit Marine Mammal Commission (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Wavetek (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Proposal & Budget for the Program of the H/D Fdn (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - O'Harn Company (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Equipment List 1983 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Tank Designs (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Underwater Monitor (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - US Dept of Agriculture (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Dolphin-Human Relationship and LSD-25 2nd Int'l Conf. on use of LSD in Psych... May 65 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Charles Tart (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Photos & Letters Re: Photos (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Cetacea Belugas (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Past Workshops (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Human/Dolphin Foundation Report #4: Dec 1, 1980-Jan 11, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Newsletter Potential Photos (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Von Foerster, Heinz (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Seti & Ceti (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Verbal Behavior (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Series 3. Conferences, workshops, catalogs, etc., 1980-1982
  - Marine World Monthly Workshops (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - European Trip - 1980 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Marks, John (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Morgane, Peter - Advisor (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Nagel, Eugene L. (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - National Medical Library, Bethesda, MD (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Silverberg Rosen & Leon Law Offices (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Redwood City Financial Work Scholar Program (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - General Telephone - Paid (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Bernstein & Schwartz - Legal (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - Workshops - Publicity - Write Ups (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - Michael S. Pratter, Attorney (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Texas Instruments Operating Manual (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Conferences-Complete (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Neural Prosthesis Workshop-Conference October, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Cal. Museum of Science and Industry, March 8, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - The Esalen Catalog (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - The Paul Winter Consort (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Dartington Conference - England, April 8, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Wrekin Trust - England April 19, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - UCLA - May 9th, 1980, The Paul Winter Consort (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - La Canada College, May 31, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Interface - October 18 & 19, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Workshop--Mandala Society "Exploring the Limits of Consciousness" (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - OJAI Foundation, March 7, May 2 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Minnesota May 17-21 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Everett College, Washington State, 4/6/1982 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Center for the Healing Arts, October 29-30 1982 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Kauai Workshop Publicity (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Blank Workshop Contracts (Box 35, Folder 19)